Guide to the H. William Fogle papers, 1967-2015.
Fogle, H. William papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
H. William Fogle papers, 1967-2015.
6781
Fogle, H. William.
2.4 cubic feet, 4 volumes, 1 folder, 4 CD.
Printed material, manuscripts, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Memoir, "Letter to Ellie - 2007," recounting a love affair with a young woman from Connecticut that took place during the author's undergraduate years at Cornell University. The story, largely told through letters and poems, begins with his boyhood in the Shenandoah Valley of Virginia, recalls their 1967 meeting in New Haven, and continues through his service with the U.S. Marine Corps and subsequent studies at Corpus Christi College, Cambridge University. The tale ends with his marriage to another when his career path takes him to Scott Paper Co. in Philadelphia, Pa. Also, three volumes containing the original letters, postcards, telegrams, drafts, and memorabilia transcribed or reproduced in the memoir.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Homer William Fogle, Jr. was born in 1948 and graduated from Cornell University, Class of 1970.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Memoir, "Letter to Ellie - 2007," recounting a love affair with a young woman from Connecticut that took place during the author's undergraduate years at Cornell University. The story, largely told through letters and poems, begins with his boyhood in the Shenandoah Valley of Virginia, recalls their 1967 meeting in New Haven, and continues through his service with the U.S. Marine Corps and subsequent studies at Corpus Christi College, Cambridge University. The tale ends with his marriage to another when his career path takes him to Scott Paper Co. in Philadelphia, Pa. Also, three volumes containing the original letters, postcards, telegrams, drafts, and memorabilia transcribed or reproduced in the memoir.
Documents relating to the 1967 Residential Club fire at Cornell, including a description of his involvement in the story. Also, a CD with his project files.
Originals and bound volume of "A Gentleman's Guide to Writing the Christmas Letter".
Originals and bound volumes titled "No Second Act" of transcribed letters, postcards and messages between the author and his estranged college girlfriend - assembled as a sequel to "Letter to Ellie - 2007".
Originals and bound volumes titled "Dear Gobbler" of primarily forty-five years of correspondence between DKE Brothers Fogle and Simpson from 1970 to 2015.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fogle, H. William.; Bucher, Candace Leigh (Kane), 1946-1974; Etter, Eleanor, 1947-; Etter, Eleanor, 1947-; Fogle, Irene Susan Pasternak, 1952-; Fogle, Irene Susan Pasternak, 1952-; Simpson, David John, 1948-; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University; Corpus Christi College (University of Cambridge); Corpus Christi College (University of Cambridge); Delta Kappa Epsilon. Delta Chi Chapter (Cornell University).; Elmira College; Elmira College.; Scott Paper Company; Scott Paper Company.; United States. Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps.; United States. Marine Corps; United States. Marine Corps.; United States. Marine Corps; United States. Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps
Subjects:
Love.; Unrequited love.; Love-letters.; Love poetry, American.; Love; Love-letters; Love poetry, American; Students; Unrequited love
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 2 and 3 are restricted to the permission of the Director of the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Letter to Ellie
  - Volume: Letter to Ellie, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Three additional volumes containing material reproduced in Letter to Ellie, Undated (Box 1)
- Series II. No Second Act
  - Images used in memoir, Date unknown (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Access restrictions apply.
  - CD's containing additional project files, Date unknown; CD-2429-2431 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, 2010-2013 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - H. William Fogle and Eleanor correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Candace Bucher material, 1974, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series III. A Gentleman's Guide to Writing the Christmas Letter
  - Document originals, 1971-2015 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - H. William Fogle published articles, letters to editor and rebuttals, 1970-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Volume: A Gentleman's Guide to Writing the Christmas Letter, 2016 (Box 4)
- Series IV. Dear Gobbler
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2008 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Spiral-bound booklet: Fogle’s Places: A Photographic Journey, 2016-06-15 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photos and photo key, 2016-06-15 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Volume I and II of Dear Gobbler, 2016 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Volume III-V of Dear Gobbler, 2016 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Volume VI of Dear Gobbler, 2016 (Box 9)
- Series V. Additional Material
  - 1967 Residential Club fire research files, Date unknown; DVD-1589 (Box 3)